# Maxwell Muhanda

Software Engineer

ajaybullec@gmail.com

0

in 7



## About

My name is Maxwell Muhanda, a full-stack web developer currently based in Kenya. My Passion for software is 100% driven by ideas i dream of and my want to make them a reality. I strive to deliver high quality code alongside a great user experience in every product I build.

I also do Digital marketing, particularly web SEO and social media marketing all inspired with current industry tools and the ability to create engagements over through technology.

Outside of programming, I enjoy travelling, video games and watching Football. I treasure the feeling of making wonderful memories.

# Portolio

#### Instruct 7

An uber for legal services

#### Portfolio website 7

my personal website

### Personality Test O 7

Get to know your personality



## Pong Africa <sup>↗</sup>

Telecommunication company Landing

## Vue Calculator O 7

Vue is composition api calculator



# Vue-Flask IPAddress tracker O

track any devices by IP Address



## **Work Experience**

## **Instruct** Backend Developer

Apr 2022 - Present | Remote

#### Backend & DevOps engineer

- Developed a Django REST api server to validate user registration and match lawyers to clients, being the main logic.
- Implemented AWS to allow easy iteration in company cloud infrastructure.
- Developed code following common security practices and development design patterns
- Ensured the performance, quality, and responsiveness of 6+ microservice containers

Pong Agencies Limited Digital Marketing & Software Development Executive

Oct 2021 - Sep 2022 | Nairobi Kenya

- Launched SEO campaign for high volume and long-tail keywords that generated unique visitors and growth of company website and online store
- Led transition from AWS to Hostinger shared Hosting, saving company KSH 5000+ monthly and increasing load speeds by an average of 38%
- Monitored social media and Google SEO analytics to adjust post time, location, and various media to grow target platform by 20,000+ followers in less than a year
- Strategized, developed, and managed digital marketing across Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook

Office of the Attorney General Industrial Attachment

May 2021 - Aug 2021 | Nairobi, Kenya

Provided technical support on HR department

# Skills

Frontend Typescript, Javascript, Vue, TailwindCSS

Backend Django, Flask, REST, MySQL, Nginx

Marketing SEO, Analytics, SEM, Social Media

DevOps Firebase, AWS, Linode, Docker, Kubernates

Languages Python, JavaScript, SQL

# Education

Marketing, Bachelor of Commerce, St Paul's University

Aug 2018 - Nov 2021

KCSE, High School Diploma, Musingu Boys

Feb 2014 - Nov 2017

# Certificates

Agile Scrum Master(ASM®), Simplilearn

2022-05-01

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing, Google Digital Garage

2020-10-01

Introduction to Git and Github, Coursera

2019-11-01

## Interests

web3

Blockchain

**Forex** 

Gaming

# Languages

Kiswahili (Native speaker), English (Fluent)

Online Version

Last updated at December 26th 2022, 7:02:25 pm